酒を持っていった時
The Galassias were receptive when you brought them the whiskey?
ガラッシアの対応は悪くなかったんだろう
Yeah, they said the stuff with
Ronaldo was water under the bridge.
あぁ ロナルドのことは水に流すと
I remember a guy named Strega
who came to the funeral.
やつの組織には確かストレーガとかいうのが来てたな
He's Don Galassia's nephew and Ronaldo's cousin.
ドン ガラッシアの甥 ロナルドの従兄弟だ
Did you meet him in Chicago?
シカゴではやつとも会ったのか
Avilio.
アヴィリオ
Yeah.
Did you get any sleep?
寝てねぇのか
Either way, we'd best proceed with caution.
いずれにしろ 慎重に進めた方がいい
No need to be so nervous. Right, Uncle?
そんな ビビることねぇだろう なぁ 伯父貴
Well, they are the big family that controls Chicago.
いや シカゴを牛耳るビッグファミリーだ
We don't want to do anything to offend them.
ご機嫌を損ねるのはまずい
They're here.
おいでなすったぞ
kanjou ni tsukeru
I can assign whatever name I wish
namae wa jiyuu dane
To these emotions.
hora kawarihateta
See, they've already ceased to change.
kesenai boku no
The trigger of
tsumi no hikigane ga
My unrepentable sins
toketeshimaisou de
Seems ready to melt away,
nikushimi ga kieteshimattara
But if this hatefulness fades,
kimi o korosenai kara
I'll lose my chance to kill you.
kako o tannou shiteiru
I'm experiencing every moment of my past,
tsumi ga tsukutta boku ni kawaru tame ni
Trying to become the person who created these sins
ASL no naifu de
With an ASL knife.
kioku no signal kizamareteru noni
Despite the signal carved into my memories,
itami sae keshisatteshimau kizuna no spiral
Even the pain is erased away by this spiral of causality.
Having wandered in, I begin to fade... ceasing to be myself.
mayoikonda boku wa boku de kietekureteiku
All for Nothing
一切白費
It's an honor to meet you, Don Galassia.
お会い出来て光栄です ドン ガラッシア
You're Vince's boy, eh?
君がヴィンスの息子か?
You look just like he did as a youth.
若い頃にそっくりだ
About Ronaldo—
ロナルドのことは...
Don't sweat it.
You took responsibility for that yourself.
気にするな お前がその手でケジメを付けたんだ
これからはお互い前を向いて
Let's both move forward and build a relationship together.
関係を築いていこうじゃないか
I'm grateful to hear you say that.
そう言っていただけると
My nephew Strega is a capable man.
甥のストレーガ 出来るやつだ
I hope you youngsters get along.
若いもの同士 仲良くやってくれよ
Good to see you, Don Galassia.
これは ドンガラッシア
Don Vanetti!
ドン ヴァネッティ
Or rather, you've named Nero the don now, haven't you?
いや ドンはネロに譲られたのでしたな
厄介ことはあいつに押し付けて
Yes, I've pushed all the work onto him so that I can take it easy.
のんびりさせてもらってます
How I envy you!
それは羨ましい
How about a drink?
一杯どうです
That's the stuff Avilio brought us, eh?
アヴィリオが持ってきた酒だな
I'm sure it'll be popular in Chicago, too.
あれはきっと シカゴでも評判に...
Are you all right?
大丈夫ですか
I beg your pardon...
お見苦しいところ
Are you ready to come to Chicago?
シカゴに来る決心は付いたか
I could never abandon this place.
ここを捨てるような真似は
Nero Vanetti.
ネロ ヴァネッティ
He seems like an interesting guy,
面白そうなやつだ
だが ああいうお人好しの甘ちゃん
but a naïve child like him will trip up sooner or later.
いずれ足元をすくわれる
Look ahead to the future Avilio.
先を見るんだアヴィリオ 将来を
This town is too small for you.
この町は お前には狭すぎる
You're not looking too good.
だいぶ顔色が悪いぞ
Any changes to the plan tomorrow?
明日の段取りに変更は
No. Their room is the furthest down the hall on the second floor.
ない 奴等の部屋は二階の一番奥だ
ここのドアは銃を通さねから
The door is bulletproof, so you'll need to get inside to kill Vincent.
ヴィンセントをやるには中に入んなきゃならん
And it's the one door without an outside knob.
それにこの部屋だけ ノブはねぇ
鍵ぁなければ
It's set up so that you can't get in
from the outside without a key.
外からは開けられない仕組みになってる
They'll finish off Del Toro, who'll be guarding the door.
アイツ等がドア前のテル ドロを始末する
That's when their savior, the great Avilio, will appear.
そこで救世主アヴィリオ様が現れる
If anything goes wrong, Nero should open the door.
問題事が起きれば ネロは扉を開けるはずだ
ガラッシアを先に逃がし
I let Galassia escape first, then kill Vincent, who can't run, and Nero.
走れないヴィンセントとネロをやる
Add your name to this.
これにあんたの名前を足してくれ
If your name is on it, it means you're my enemy.
ここに名前があれば 俺の敵ってことになる
You get it, right?
分かるだろう
You don't miss a trick.
抜け目の無い野郎だ
You were there that day as well, weren't you?
あの時 あんたもいたんだな
You knew?
お前知ってたのか?
Yeah, but I also know you didn't fire a shot.
あぁ だが銃を抜かなかったことも知ってる
Back then, Vincent was colluding with the Galassias.
あの時 ヴィンセントは裏でガラッシアと通じてた
He killed your family because your father found out.
そして それに勘付いたお前の親父と家族をやった
You should be the one to kill Vincent and Nero.
やつとネロはお前がやるべきだ
It's the only thing that makes sense.
そうじゃなきゃ筋が通らね
Don't rush me. Everything in its proper order.
急かすなよ 物には順序がある
What are you talking about?
何の話だ
Nothing.
いや
You sure we can count on him?
任せて大丈夫なのか
If anything happens to the don—
ドンにもしものことがあったら...
He's capable.
腕は確かだ
And once Vincent's dead...
ヴィンセントをやったら
明後日からは
In two days, you'll be the one unifying the family.
お前がファミリーをまとめることになる
Don't mess it up.
しっかりやれよ
Sure.
Unlike Nero, I do as I'm told.
ネロと違って 俺は聞き分けがいいぜ
Does Don Galassia know about this?
ドン ガラッシアはこのこをを
知らなくていい
He doesn't have to. Old Uncle's
gone soft, through and through.
うちの伯父貴もすっかり甘くなった
Nero, might I have a moment?
ネロ ちょっといいか
Is this about Avilio?
アヴィリオのことか
Yeah. I think we should take him off security at the playhouse.
あぁ やつは劇場の警備から外した方がいい
Why?
なぜ
I think he resents us over what happened with Corteo.
やつはコルテオのことで俺達を恨んでいる
You, especially.
特にお前を
Take my advice and—
悪いことは言わないが...
Yesterday, he cleared all suspicion on himself.
昨日自分の手で疑いを晴らしただろう
What good would it do him to resent us now?
今更恨んだところで どうなるもんでもねぇ
He's like an empty shell.
あいつはもう抜け殻みたいなもんだ
I'll give Avilio something to live for.
アヴィリオの生き甲斐は俺が与える
How are you feeling?
具合はどうだ
Well enough, today.
今日は大分いい
Did you speak to the doctor?
医者には会ったか?
He says you'll be right as rain soon.
すぐに良くなるとせさ
Don't hide it.
隠すな
I know I'm on my way out.
もうすぐ くたばるのは分かってる
Years ago, I killed my best friend and his family with my own hands.
かつて俺は 親友とその家族をこの手にかけた
If I hadn't killed Testa then,
あの時テスタをやらなければ
the family would have been
swallowed up by the Galassias.
今頃ファミリーはガラッシアに呑まれていた
The last seven years,
あれから七年
I've kept telling myself that.
そう言い聞かせてきた
だがな 今になって見ると
However looking back, I wonder if
there might've been another way.
別の道があったんじゃないのか
If, maybe, I didn't have to kill him.
やつをやらずに済んだんじゃないのか
That's all I think about.
そんなことばかり
Dad.
親父
The Vanetti name is more important than anything.
バネッチィの名は何よりも重い
More than friends, more than parents and siblings.
友よりも 親兄弟よりも
I'm ready to do what I must.
覚悟はでき出る
I'm back.
ただいま
I've been waiting for this day for so long.
ずっとこの日を待っていた
Ah... But have I really?
いや 本当に待ってたのか
I can't even tell anymore.
もう分からない
What did I come back here for?
いったい何のために戻ってきたのか
What have I been killing for?
何のために殺してきたのか
Well, Corteo?
ま コルテオ
Tomorrow, it all ends.
明日 全てが終わる
Hey! Stay back!
おい よってくんな
Don Vanetti!
ドン バネッチィ
It's been three years since
you were last seen in public.
公の場に姿を現わした三年ぶりですが
Could you say a few words?
何か一言
It's beautiful.
素晴らしい
Yeah.
It's Galassia!
ガラッシアだ
He's here!
来たぞ
How do you like the playhouse?
どうだ この劇場は
I modeled it after La Scala in Milan.
ミラノのスカラ座をモデルにした
You called in an Italian architect to build it, right?
イタリアから建築家を招いて建てさせたんだろう
You've told me fifty times already.
もう50回が聞いたぜ
This playhouse was my dream.
この劇場は俺の夢だった
Yeah. I must say I envy you.
正直 羨ましいやつだぜ お前は
You've got everything.
何でも手に入れやがってよ
さって
And it'll all be secured once we work things out with Galassia.
これでガラッシアとの話し合いが纏まれば
万事安泰だ
I'm sure Testa Lagusa would understand.
テスタラグーザも分かってくれるさ
Look at them, swinging those things around.
ったく あんなもんぶらさげやがって
野暮なやつらだせ
They don't have a drop of class.
What choice do they have?
しょうがないだろう
They can't risk anything happening tonight.
今夜は何かあっちゃ困るからな
Start time, eh?
そろそろ始まるか
I'm going to have a look around.
一回りしてくる
私はローレスの市長であること
I've never been more proud to be mayor of Lawless.
これほど誇らしく思った日はありません
Now, once more,
それでは もう一度
let's have a round of applause for Mr. Vincent Vanetti!
ヴィンセント バネッチィ氏に盛大な拍手を
Very impressive.
大したものだ
We don't even have a theater this nice in Chicago.
シカゴにもこれほどの劇場はない
I'm honored.
光栄です
To a new start with the Vanetti family.
バネッチィファミリの新しい門出に
Okay, thanks.
それじゃ 頼んだぜ
Yeah. We'll swap in at 9:00 PM.
うん 21時に交替だ
Glad they're so understanding.
話の分かるやつらで助かったぜ
I'd go crazy after three hours of standing.
三時間も立ちん坊じゃ可笑しくなっちまう
Hey.
Smoke that over there!
向こうで吸ってこい
Yeah, yeah.
へい へい
Mr. Del Toro lend me a match, would you?
デル トロの旦那 マッチ貸してもらいませんか
Come on, no need to ignore me.
旦那 無視ずることはないでしょう
永遠に黙ってね
Be silent forever.
本字幕由✿花語&千夏字幕組✿共同製作
I thought so.
やはりな
You wanted to avenge Corteo, is that it?
コルテオの敵を討つつもりだったのか?
俺の仲間がネロを狙ってる たった今もな
My comrades are after Nero as we speak.
出任せを言うな
Don't change the subject.
But...
でもよ...
I didn't see the bodies of
Galassia's watchdogs up there.
あの場にはガラッシアの見張りの死体がなかった
I'm worried.
ちょっと気になるぜ
There's a letter in my jacket pocket.
内ポケットに手紙が入ってる
It's from the man who called me to this town.
俺をこの町に呼んだ男からだ
Angelo Lagusa?
アンジェロ ラグーズ
What does it say?
何で書いたんだ
"The ones who killed your father, mother, and little brother,
ローレスに眠るお前の父と母
who now rest in peace in Lawless...
そして弟を殺した者たちの名は
Vincent Vanetti, his son Nero,
ヴィンセント バネッチィ 息子のネロ
Vanno Clemente, and Ganzo Alary."
ヴァンノ クレメッテ そしてガンゾ アラリ
Who sent this?
誰からだ
Who is this best friend of Testa Lagusa?
このテスタ ラグーザの親友と誰だ
I'll call Nero and Uncle Ganzo!
ネロとガンゾ叔父きを呼ぼう
Wait.
待て
Don't call Nero.
ネロを呼ぶな
I can't believe it. Avilio did?
信じられない アヴィリオ
Barbero said not to call Nero.
バルベロはネロを呼ぶなって
No, call him.
いや 呼んで来い
But...
でも...
Nero's the don, not Barbero.
ドンはネロじゃ バルベロじゃねい
What happened? Explain this.
何があった 説明しろ
As I thought, he was after Nero.
やっぱり ネロを狙っていました
And Don Vincent, and you.
ドン ヴィンセントやあなたも
Whoever sent this letter is behind all this.
こいつにその手紙を送ったやつが黒幕です
Do you have any ideas?
心当たりは
Not one.
さあな
Where's Tigre?
ティグレは
He went to get Nero.
ネロを呼びに行った
Why?!
何故
Nero should get to decide what to do.
どうするかはネロに決めさせる
This boy was his right hand, after all.
こいつは右腕だったしなぁ
No! Nero won't kill him!
だめだ ネロにはこいつは殺せない
Now, calm down, Barbero.
おい 落ち着けバルベロ
Vanno and Del Toro, and the
deaths of so many others...
ヴァンノもデル トロもほかのやつらの死も
He was behind them all!
すべてこいつがやったことだ
Nero said you were like an empty shell.
お前は抜け殻のようだとネロはそう言っていた
He said he would give you something to live for.
お前に生き甲斐を与えるともなぁ
You drove Nero mad!
お前がネロを狂わせた
If you hadn't shown up...
お前が現れなければ
You're pathetic.
見苦しいやつだ
Devil who possessed the family and infested Nero's mind...
ファミリーに取り付き ネロの心に巣くう悪魔め
I'll protect Nero myse—
ネロを俺が守
Guess it's all over.
ぶち壊しだな
Where did you mess up?
どこでへまをしやがった
Actually... I think things are going perfectly.
いえ むしろお誂え向きの状況じゃないか
Nero.
ネロ
Excuse me.
失礼
What's wrong?
どうした
Barbero's got Avilio...
バルベロがアヴィリオを...
Uncle?
おじき
He got away. You just missed him.
どうやら 入れ違いでに逃げられた
H-Hey!
What the hell? This is awful! Damn it!
んだよ ひでえじゃないか チクショウ
Avilio...
アヴィリオ...
やつの狙いはヴィンセントと俺
It seems he is after Vincent, me, and you.
お前のようだ
So he's going after the don?
じゃドンのところに?
But he can't get inside without the key.
だが あの部屋は鍵がなきゃ中に入れねぇ
Let's send someone just to be safe.
念のため人をやろ
I'll find him and kill him!
見つけ出せ 俺がぶっ殺してやる
Hey, hey.
What's going on here?
これはどういうことだ
Is that body a stage prop?
その死体は舞台の小道具が
もしもドンに何かあったら
If anything happens to the don...
You know what'll happen, right?
分かってんだろうなあ
If I were him, I'd go with a rifle.
俺なら ライフルだな
I could snipe him easily from the box across from his.
対岸の部屋から楽に狙撃できる
Nero!
ネロ
We'd better get searching, too.
俺らも探さねえとなぁ
Tigre, check the fourth floor!
ティグレ 4階を見てこい
Right!
Excuse me.
申し訳ありません
I was told to lead you two outside through the back entrance.
お2人を裏手から外へお連れするようにと
Where's Del Toro?
デル トロは
I don't know. He isn't here.
さ ここには居りません
Who are you?
お前は
Avilio.
アヴィリオ
Bring Nero here.
ネロを連れてこい
Don Galassia, please.
ドン ガラッシアお願いします
We don't have time.
時間がないんです
Watch your tongue!
弁えろ
Now, no need to be so angry.
まあ そういきり立つこともないでしょう
I know the man well, myself.
私もよく知る男です
And he's your son's right hand, I hear.
それにご子息の右腕とか
Looks like we've reached the climax,
クライマックスのようなあ
though it didn't quite go by the script.
筋書きとは違うが
What's going on here?
どういうことだ
This man killed my family.
俺がこいつに家族を殺された
I don't know you.
お前など知らん
My father's name was Testa Lagusa.
父ならテスタ ラグーザ
This is great! Is he part of the performance?
これはいい 舞台から出てきたのか
He just keeps getting more interesting!
まったく面白い男だ
I returned to this town for the sake of this day.
今日の日を迎えるためこの町に帰ってきた
This time, I'm the one who'll take everything away.
今度は俺がすべてを奪う番だ
Someone call a doctor!
誰か早く医者を
Damn you!
貴様
Wait! That wasn't—
待って 違うんだ...
Just what is going on here?
いったい何かどうなってんだ
Well, it's not a bad development.
まあ 悪くない展開か
Finish the Vanettis.
バネッチィを片付けろ
Nero... Nero!
ネロ ネロ
Dad!
親父
Hang in there!
しっかりしろ
Nero...
ネロ
It's over.
終わりだ
Dad...
親父
It was all for nothing.
すべてが無駄ごと
Corteo...
コルテオ
I did it.
やったぞ